# Hankook Lee

Homepage: https://hankook.github.io Github: https://github.com/hankook Email: hankook.lee@kaist.ac.kr

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I am a Ph.D. candidate in the School of Electrical Engineering at Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST), advised by Jinwoo Shin. My research has investigated how to learn deep neural networks with limited human prior knowledge. Specifically, my interests include self-supervised learning [2,6-8], transfer learning [1-2,7], data augmentation [2,7], and real-world applications with limited labels [3-6].

### **EDUCATION**

### M.S. & Ph.D.

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2022

School of Electrical Engineering, KAIST, Republic of Korea Advised by Prof. Jinwoo Shin

B.S. Mar. 2010 - Feb. 2016

Mathematics and Computer Science (double major), KAIST, Republic of Korea GPA: 3.93/4.3 (Magna Cum Laude)

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **External Collaborator**

Mar. 2021 - May. 2021

Honglak Lee (University of Michigan), Kibok Lee (AWS), Kimin Lee (Berkeley)

• Developed a self-supervised learning algorithm for improving transferability of learned representations [7].

## Visiting Student

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology (SAIT), Republic of Korea

• Developed ML-based retrosynthesis algorithms [4-5].

## Research and Development Engineer

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2014

Watcha Inc., Republic of Korea

- Built an automatic movie tagging system using Latent Dirichlet Allocation.
- Built a movie rating prediction system using non-negative matrix factorization.

# (\*: equal contribution)

PUBLICATIONS [8] Sukmin Yun, Hankook Lee, Jaehyung Kim and Jinwoo Shin, "Patchlevel Representation Learning for Selfsupervised Vision Transformers", IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), Oral Presentation, 2022

- [7] Hankook Lee, Kibok Lee, Kimin Lee, Honglak Lee and Jinwoo Shin, "Improving Transferability of Representations via AugmentationAware SelfSupervision", Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021
- [6] Junsu Kim, Sungsoo Ahn, Hankook Lee and Jinwoo Shin, "Self-Improved Retrosynthetic Planning", International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2021
- [5] Hankook Lee, Sungsoo Ahn, Seung-Woo Seo, You Young Song, Eunho Yang, Sung Ju Hwang and Jinwoo Shin, "RetCL: A Selectionbased Approach for Retrosynthesis via Contrastive Learning", International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2021
- [4] Seung-Woo Seo\*, You Young Song\*, June Yong Yang, Seohui Bae, Hankook Lee, Jinwoo Shin, Sung Ju Hwang and Eunho Yang, "GTA: Graph Truncated Attention for Retrosynthesis", AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021

[3] Sungsoo Ahn, Junsu Kim, **Hankook Lee** and Jinwoo Shin, "Guiding Deep Molecular Optimization with Genetic Exploration", Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020

[2] Hankook Lee, Sung Ju Hwang and Jinwoo Shin, "Self-supervised Label Augmentation via Input Transformations", International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2020

[1] Yunhun Jang\*, **Hankook Lee**\*, Sung Ju Hwang and Jinwoo Shin, "Learning What and Where to Transfer", International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2019

# HONORS & AWARDS

Winner

2019

Qualcomm-KAIST Innovation Award, Republic of Korea

### **ICPC** World Finalist

2013

International Collegiate Programming Contest World Finals, St. Petersburg, Russia

## 1st Place (2012), 2nd Place (2010)

2010-2012

International Collegiate Programming Contest Asia Daejeon Regional, Republic of Korea

Gold Prize 2009

Problem Solving Division, Korea Olympiad in Informatics (KOI), Republic of Korea

# ACADEMIC SERVICES

## Conference Reviewer

NeurIPS (2020-2022), ICLR (2020-2022), ICML (2020-2022), AAAI (2022), Self-supervised Learning Workshops (ICML 2021, NeurIPS 2021, ECCV 2022)

## Journal Reviewer

ACM ToMPECS, IEEE TPAMI

# INVITED TALKS

"Self-supervised Label Augmentation via Input Transformations",

2021

Samsung Electronics DIT Center, Republic of Korea

2020

"Learning What and Where to Transfer". Samsung Electronics DIT Center, Republic of Korea

"Learning What and Where to Transfer",

2019

Summer Annual Conference of the Institute of Electronics and Information Engineers (IEIE), Republic of Korea

"Anytime Neural Prediction via Slicing Networks Vertically", 2018 NAVER Labs, Republic of Korea

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

**TA**, "Segmentation and Object Detection", Samsung DS AI Expert Program 2020 **TA**, "Optimization and Regulaization", SK Hynix ML Program 2019

**TA**, "Transfer and Multitask Learning", Samsung DS AI Expert Program **TA**, "Regression", Seongnam-KAIST AI Program

2019
2018

TA, "Regression", KB-KAIST AI Program 2017-2018

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

C/C++, Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow